hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says a semicircle and a quarter circle
inside of a square how long is the black
tangent line this is another puzzle from
Katrina a I'm trying to solve all of
these if you want to try this one on
your own pause it right now because I'm
going to solve it in three 2 1 first
let's copy down and let's focus on the
radius of this quarter Circle they're
telling us right here that it's equal to
8 and let's shift it over here to this
point of tangency and that means it's
going to be at right angles and from
here let's duplicate this one we're
going to do something different on this
one and this one for the top one let's
look at the radius of five and let's
shift it down here and then let's look
at this side length and let's call that
s for side length and since it's a
square we know both these side lengths
are equal to S and then last let's
complete this triangle and we know this
is a right angle because it's a square
we don't know this angle down here so
let's call it Theta and that's going to
be the same angle as this down here so
this one's also Theta and while we're
down here let's draw this side and we
know that's equal to s because it's a
side of the square let's bring this down
and keep it parallel and then let's
complete this triangle and we know this
is also a right triangle because it's
parallel to the top next let's try to
find this angle inside here since this
is a right triangle and this acute angle
is Theta that leaves 90 minus Theta for
the other angle since this is a right
angle and this piece is 90 minus Theta
that means that this angle in this
triangle will also be equal to Theta and
now we have two congruent triangles
let's focus on those triangles for this
triangle up here on the hypotenuse the
five and the eight will add together to
give us 13 and now let's rotate this one
now we have these two triangles lined up
and they are congruent the reason we
know they're congruent is because of Asa
which stands for angle side angle that's
because we have these two angles
congruent we have these two sides
congruent and we have these two angles
congruent and now since we know these
two triangles are congruent that means
if this side is 13 this side is also 13
and this side length right here is the
same thing as this side length right
here so we've now solved the problem
it's equal to 13 units let's put a box
around it and there is a part two to
this problem I also found the area of
this square if you want to check out
that video I'll try to put the link up
here and also put it in the description
how exciting